# Richard Chiriboga

Flushing, NY 11355
(347) 326-4434
RichardChiriboga@gmail.com
https://Linkedin.com/in/richardchiriboga
https://richardchiriboga.com

Web Project Manager and front-end developer with extensive experience working across global corporate, non-profit and boutique agency environments. Expertise in leading website restructuring, development projects, corporate intranet builds and content management plans through the complete lifecycle. Known for being a trusted partner across global matrixed organizations and having the ability to communicate complex information to both technical and non-technical users, including information pertaining to change management, stakeholder engagement and governance. Hispanic marketing and social media expertise: Created award-winning website CorrienteLatina.com. Fluent in English, with intermediate Spanish fluency.

## **Skills**

Technical Management, Web Development Management, Waterfall / Agile Methodologies, Digital Media / Marketing, Basecamp, Front-End Web Development, GitHub, PHP / MySQL, WordPress, Jira, HTML / CSS / Javascript, jQuery / angularJS, Certified ScrumMaster, Luminate CMS / Online, Bilingual (English / Spanish)

# **Experience**

04/2018 - 8/2018

# Independent Consulting | New York, NY

Work as a Technical Project Manager and freelance web developer for global financial services companies in New York City.

Client: Chubb | Position: Intranet Migration Manager

- Serve as liaison to Chubb's IT Department, helping Communications to better understand technical aspects of an
  intranet platform migration as it relates to change management, stakeholder engagement, governance, security and
  workflows.
- Identify Communications' role in migrating Chubb's global intranet to a new platform.
- Assist the SCRUM Master and Product Owner, organizing and creating backlogs and subtasks for sprint iterations.

Client: Jane Street | Position: Web Developer

 Work on updated corporate website and new-hire website as a Web Developer using HTML, CSS (SASS), Javascript, Markdown, Liquid, Jekyll.

# 11/2016 - 12/2017

## Senior Manager, Web Development | Avon Breast Cancer Crusade, New York, NY

Managed web development team along with all project lifecycles while bridging the gap between cross-functional internal and external stakeholders to deliver a seamless digital solution, using both waterfall and agile methodologies.

- Managed brand IT relationships and strategy with internal and remote third-party vendors across various projects. This included project SOWs, resources, budgets and conflict resolution.
- Managed all web properties, including the creation of the corporate website and the flagship AVON 39 website, through which nearly \$30 million was donated.
- Implemented and standardized web design/development workflow to ensure updates and new functionality were pushed seamlessly.

- Led web development tasks, including user interface, systems architecture, platform logic, API development and maintenance for all web properties.
- Standardized email signature throughout company by developing an online form that allowed staff to create a standardized email signature and easily add it to the Gmail environment.
- Led IT crisis management, including SSL and payment gateway issues with Elavon, Blackbaud and PayFlow Pro.
- Developed an online check-in system used throughout the 2015-2017 event seasons. The "Check-In Friday" system allowed volunteers and staff to manage and report on participants and crew during event weekends.

#### 06/2011 - 11/2016

# Manager, Web Technologies | Avon Products, Inc., New York, NY

Managed all web properties owned by Corporate Communications, including the "InsideAvon" global intranet and corporate website, AvonCompany.com.

- Oversaw the creation of internal and external digital platforms for New Avon, after the North America business was separated from Avon Products, Inc. and brought under management of investment firm Cerberus Capital Management.
- Addressed corporate intranet (InsideAvon) issues by spearheading and leading the front-end development effort to create a
  custom CMS on .NET MVC, Twitter Bootstrap, jQuery and knockout.js. Equipped with movable dynamic widgets and a simple
  image manipulator, it enabled content owners to update their respective websites effortlessly. InsideAvon housed 25 market and
  functional intranets.
- Assisted in designing and developing a lightweight Learning Management System (LMS) used to help Avon's corporate employees. Helped write RFP requirements and project scope.
- Assisted in designing and developing a Policy Portal to house all global policies and procedures. This included content translated into 19 languages and intuitive search via SOLR.
- Was part of the B2B / B2C development team developing front-end user interfaces for products in Latin America on the Magnolia platform using angularJS, jQuery and Twitter Bootstrap.
- Improved the associate digital experience by utilizing the latest trends to create a holistic socially interactive digital workplace. Served on steering committee to roll out Microsoft Office 365 to over 30,000 associates to replace Lotus Notes.
- Helped plan all aspects of project development, including scope, objectives, deliverables, tasks, budgets, resources, schedules, coordinating cross-functional teams and managing dependencies.
- Managed Web Portals using various Content Management Systems for global functions, including Human Resources, Finance, Legal and Global Travel Security.
- Served as liaison between IT teams, design team and business product owners to help gather requirements and create spec documents for critical projects.

### 06/2007 - 07/2010

## Senior Web Developer | THAT Agency, West Palm Beach, FL

Worked directly with the president and project manager on all aspects from concept to creation for client websites.

- Served on leadership team to guide company on which current technologies to select, enabling agency to distinguish itself from
  other web boutiques by creating a custom Content Management System built in-house and then customizing for each client's
  specific needs.
- Wrote technical blogs that led some of my web development work to be featured on "Top 10" lists for HTML/CSS/jQuery.

# **Education**

05/2015

**Certified ScrumMaster** 

Scrum Alliance, New York, NY

1993-1996

**Informational Systems** 

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY

## **Awards**

- 2016 Tecla Award for "Best Latino News and Culture" website by Hispanicize / Telemundo.
- 2017 Jack Daniel's Neighborhood Flavors Honoree in the "Movers & Shakers" category for helping the Hispanic community in Queens, NY.